一个男生吃了25个装有泻药的巧克力饼，把肾吃出毛病了？
A boy ate 25 laxative brownies in one hour, this is what happened to his kidneys
“包哥”，14岁，进了急诊室，心率异常
BG is a fourteen-year-old boy presenting to the emergency room with an abnormal heart rate
他哥Nate告诉值班护士之前十小时包哥已经拉了八次，路都走不稳
His older brother Nate tells the admitting nurse that BG had defecated eight times in the last ten hours before stumbling around confused
包哥和他朋友打赌15分钟吃10个有泻药的巧克力饼
You see BG and his friends decided to challenge each other first to poo poo
最先拉稀的俩人明天要女装上学
wears a tutu where friends would eat ten laxatives filled brownies within 15 minutes
and the first two to poop would be deemed full of crap and will have to wear a tutu to school the next day
当然啦现在可爱的男孩子谁没穿过女装呀
Clearly this was for jokes and memes on behalf of 14 year olds
所以Nate就去买了非处方的泻药
It didn't help that Nate, the older brother, agreed to buy the laxatives over-the-counter
他姐也同意做巧克力饼
and an older sister agreed to bake the brownies
包哥作为一帮人的头头，不止想赢，还想吃得最多
BG the alpha male in his group of friends was not only gonna win the competition he was going to eat the most brownies
平均每个饼里有两粒泻药，而成人每次只让吃俩
each one having the equivalent to two laxatives tablets you only supposed to take two as the recommended adult dose
比赛开始，几位毕竟还图样的小孩开吃了
Contest day the brownies are baked and the boys with fresh-faced determination decimate them
都想显摆一下。每人吃完十个之后20分钟，大家都挺难受
eager to show each other up. 20 minutes after finishing ten brownies each one of the boys didn't feel well
有一个男生用尽全力把屎憋住，但还是没憋住
he tried as hard as he could to resist the urge to defecate but he gave in quickly
剩下几个也贼难受，包括包哥
Some of the other boys were feeling uncomfortable too and in the back of his mind
但他想显摆他不想上厕所，就笑话其他人
BG didn't feel well but the need to show up his friends was greater than his urge to use the bathroom he laughed at the
叫他们外号，然后又吃了五个饼。其中有个男生一直捂肚子
others called them derogatory names and ate five more brownies. One of the boys was clenching his stomach he was feeling
强烈腹痛，难受得都快疼哭了
major abdominal cramps it was uncomfortable he was on the verge of tears
包哥就笑他，然后又吃五个饼，现在他一共吃20个了
BG laughed in his face and a five more brownies to show him up a total of twenty brownies now. Finally the second
最后疼哭那个也忍不住上厕所了，至此两位女装大佬敲定，而大家也
boy gives in and goes to the restroom. He was the final loser. The other boys now
可以随便去上厕所了。而包哥最后为了显摆又吃了五个
free to poop without fear of losing all go used the bathrooms and BG to show up the others ate five more brownies for a
总共吃了25个带泻药的饼。过了几小时
total of 25 before finally using the bathroom himself. It's several hours later the two boys who lost the
那两个“女装大佬”感觉好些了，其他人还略难受，而包哥厉害了
competition are feeling great. Those who fought the urge to poop aren't feeling so great and worst of all BG is
他吐字不清、站不稳，这些症状出现在
acting weird. It started with him slurring his words and tripping over his feet. These started appearing after the
他第六次大号之后。此时他反映说尿跟咖啡一个色，大便也特别稀
sixth time he defecated. Around this time he reported that his urine looked like coffee that the stools became
右小腿腓肠肌疼痛、抽筋、呼吸急促
diarrhea and that he felt his right calf muscle was sore and cramping. He was found gasping for air as he
主诉心跳飞快，伴有重度头痛，别人发现他一直在挠头
complained that his heart was racing he also started to develop a massive headache and was found gripping his head
就笑话他包哥要把他脑子拉出来了。但在第八次上完厕所后
and pain. The friends laughed that BG was pooping his brains out. But after the eighth time in the bathroom he didn't
包哥没出来，实际一个小时之后朋友发现他在厕所地上昏了，于是赶紧叫救护车
come out, and in fact, an hour later he was found unconscious on the floor. The friends immediately called for an
送到了医院急诊。从既往史来看
ambulance to bring him to the emergency room where we are now. Given this past medical history
几条线索指向了目前的情况。首先包哥现在低血钾，hypo指“低”
there's several clues as to what's happening. First BG is suffering from hypokalemia, hypo meaning low, kal
kal指钾，就是周期表里的K
referring to potassium, or more formally camión as is shown by its symbol on the periodic table of elements, and emia
emia指血液内。血液内低钾元素，低血钾。包哥显然服泻药过量
meaning presence in blood, low potassium presence in blood. BG clearly overdosed on laxatives when he took 25 times the
25倍于正常成人剂量。泻药本身没啥问题，只是普通的刺激物
recommended adult dose in the brownies. The laxative he consumed was set aside, a natural stimulant, it works by causing
让结肠肌肉收缩，促进排便，同时通过把水带入结肠
the muscles of the colon to contract helping you pass a stool, but it also softens that stool by drawing water into
从而软化粪便，而这才是问题所在。因为体内的水是很多物质的溶剂
your colon. That's a problem because your body water is a soup of several chemicals an important one getting
而这个过程中被泻药排出的就是钾元素。钾和它上面的钠都是
depleted in BG's body by the laxatives is potassium. Potassium like sodium above it on the periodic table is important in
身体非常重要的给组织器官的信号。其中一种重要信号就是
signaling in the body telling tissues and organs to do things. One important signal on behalf of sodium and potassium
控制肌肉的收缩。拿这几条离体青蛙腿为例，生理上与人类的骨骼肌相似
is muscle contraction. Take for example these frog legs that muscle is physiologically similar to human
当食盐（氯化钠）撒在大腿上后，它们会抽搐收缩
skeletal muscle when salt or sodium chloride is put on these legs, they twitch and contract despite there being
尽管它们已经离体，没有大脑控制。所以钠离子促使肌肉收缩
no brain attached to these legs to control them. So sodium helps promote muscle contraction. On the other hand
而钾离子促使肌肉松弛。钾多松弛就久
potassium promotes muscle relaxation. A lot of it present means that your muscles relaxed for a very long time and
钾少就不停收缩。某种注射死刑就是
too little present means that your muscles won't stop contracting. One part of lethal injection you know that one
向心脏注射氯化钾，抑制心脏收缩
form of capital punishment is potassium chloride injected directly to the heart to prevent it
这种注射不会让心率加快，而是让它放松——永远放松。所以现在大家明白了
from contracting. That kind of injection doesn't tense your heart up. It just relaxes it, forever. You can start to see
问题是包哥低血钾，他很难让他全身肌肉
the problem here: if potassium is low in BG's blood and his muscles would have a hard time
放松下来。他右腓肠肌与腹部都在痉挛。而心脏也是块肌肉
relaxing them. He's having cramps both in his abdomen and his right calf muscle. His heart is a muscle too and it's
现在也心律不齐，因为没有足够的信号让心脏舒张，这导致
beating irregularly because it doesn't have sufficient resources to signal relaxation. When his heart is beating
他大脑供氧跟着不足，于是昏倒在厕所地上
irregularly, the amount of oxygen getting to his brain is decreased. He's drifting in and out of consciousness
问题可不小，包哥得了横纹肌溶解症，rhabdo指横纹，这里指
Something very severe is happening. BG is suffering from rhabdomyolysis, rhabdo meaning striated, or in this case
骨骼肌，myo指肌肉，lysis指溶解，横纹肌溶解症。这病有生命危险
skeletal, myo meaning muscle and lysis meaning break down skeletal muscle breakdown. This is life-threatening and
属于医疗紧急情况。起因是包哥吃泻药过量引起的低血钾症
it's a medical emergency. This is happening because of BG's hypokalemia onset by laxative overdose. With low
包哥低血钾，全身肌肉都在收缩，无论他每次运动
potassium in his blood every time he contracts any of his muscles which is every time he moves, or every time he
每次呼吸，影响了肌细胞的正常功能。
breathes, less potassium present in the blood confuses the muscle cells and they start to malfunction. Instead of
在没有钾元素进入细胞让肌肉舒张时，肌肉会让钠元素进入。而有趣的是
potassium entering the cell to signal relaxation, the muscle allows in sodium. Now the interesting thing about sodium
钠离子会形成渗透压梯度。哪里钠多，水就会去哪
is that it creates something called an osmotic gradient, which means wherever sodium is water will flow towards it
在这个小实验里，我把少量盐水装进透明管里，把透明管放进
In this small science experiment I dissolve salt in this water and place it into a tube. I submerge the tube in a pool of
半碗淡水里，过一会你会发现水流进了塑料管里，印证了我刚刚的说法
water that has no salt dissolved in it and you'll see that water flows into the tube that water follows sodium
所以包哥的肌细胞不但在失能，还在吸水膨胀。这边包哥吃泻药
So BG's muscle cells are not only malfunctioning they're also swelling with water, not only as BG having water exit his
从结肠拉出去不少水，另一边更多的部分，大概12升的水正在进入
intravascular space through his colon but another large part of his body water up to 12 liters is entering into his
他全身的肌肉里，造成严重脱水。当你脱水到这种程度，你身体里负责过滤血液
muscle causing massive dehydration. When you're dehydrated to this degree, your kidneys which are responsible for
排出废物、维持电解质平衡以及购买iPhone的肾脏就会察觉，并收缩其血管
filtering your blood removing wastes and maintaining electrolyte balance, detect this. And they constrict their own blood
来保持身体水量，这个过程叫血管收缩。这会导致肾血流量
vessels in an attempt to conserve body water. This is called vasoconstriction. This can damage the kidneys as renal
减少而损伤肾脏。肾脏供血减少，供氧就少了
perfusion is decreased. There's less blood going to the kidneys so less oxygen is getting to the tissue which
细胞就坏死了。还有一个麻烦，现在肌肉细胞差不多该吸水涨破了
can cause cell death. But here's another problem, now that the muscle cells are starting to rupture, they're releasing
它们会释放一种重要蛋白叫肌红蛋白，引发脂质过氧化
protein, an important one known as myoglobin. Myoglobin causes something called lipid peroxidation which destroys
损害外层细胞膜。总之肌红蛋白积累对身体其他部分是有毒的，但它能积累到哪？
the outer membrane of cells. In general myoglobin's buildup can be toxic to the rest of your body but where would it
既然血液全身都有，你猜会不会积累到心脏？
buildup? As the blood flows around in your body you could say maybe myoglobin could accumulate in your heart but
但心脏没东西能留住肌红蛋白。蛋白质是大分子，可能只是穿过心脏几个腔就走了
there's nothing there to catch it. Protein is a large molecule and would likely just pass through the chambers of the heart
没有留的地方自然积累不起来。那肝脏呢？肝脏就是参与蛋白质代谢的
There isn't a reservoir where it can accumulate. But how about the liver? Well the liver breaks proteins down so
更不可能积累在肝脏。但肾脏呢？肾单位，是肾脏的功能单元
it's probably not going to buildup there either. But what about the kidney? The nephron, the functional unit of the
包含很多细小管腔。它们筛出血液中的毒物
kidney contains tubules. These filter out your blood and act as a net to catch the toxins in your blood screening them into
并从尿液排出，就像这漏勺一样。如果肌红蛋白这种大分子通过就很容易
the urine. It's kind of like this strainer. If myoglobin is a large molecule then it's likely to get caught
被堵在肾单位的管腔内，破坏其细胞膜。所以当肌红蛋白到达肾单位时
in the tubules of the nephron and can cause the breakdown of cell membranes. So when myoglobin reaches the nephron it
它们聚集、堵塞在管腔内，使你肾单位的细胞膜破裂，就像把网全剪破
builds up, gunks up the tubules and ruptures the membranes of your nephrons. It's something like dissolving the net
我们称这个过程叫急性肾损伤。而深色的尿液是因为肌红蛋白含有血红素
of this strainer. We call this acute kidney injury. The reddish brown urine is because myoglobin contains heme
是一种含铁的化合物，而铁与氧气作用使你的血液变红。
a compound that has iron that's responsible for making your blood red when exposed to oxygen. The myoglobin
肌红蛋白积累在肾单位内，使管腔破裂，溢出进入尿液
builds up in the nephron and spills into your urine once it starts to damage the tubules
这表明包哥的横纹肌溶解症已经非常严重了。而他才14岁，显然还处于
This indicates that BG's rhabdomyolysis is very severe. Because he's a fourteen-year-old boy he hasn't finished
青春期，他肌肉质量比成年人低。而儿童男性罹患横纹肌溶解症概率比
puberty yet, meaning his muscle mass is lower than an adult man. In pediatric rhabdomyolysis boys have a higher risk
女性更高，因为女性肌肉量更少。而同时对于儿童患者，深色尿液症状
of getting it than girls because of decreased female muscle mass. But also for pediatric patients the discolored
很少出现，因为这需要200克肌肉组织溶解才行。
urine doesn't usually appear because it takes upwards of 200 grams of muscle to be lysed for it to appear. That's nearly
14岁熊孩子身上四两的五花肉都没了你说病得重不重。而实际上包哥
half a pound of muscle and it's very significant for any 14-year old and the fact that VG has it precipitates the
情况真的非常危急。就算肌肉溶解能治，肾损伤也不可逆。这些肾单位
urgency of the situation. While the muscle damage can be fixed, this kidney injury is irreversible. Those nephrons
彻底坏掉了，无法再生。包哥过滤血液代谢废物的能力大打折扣
won't come back. They don't regenerate. BG's capacity to filter metabolic wastes in his blood is quickly waning and this
当肾脏代谢能力降低无法过滤废物时，就会发生酸中毒
is a problem. When the kidneys aren't removing wastes it's a vector for things like metabolic acidosis where the pH of
血液pH值会下降。造成营养不良、酶失活、最后死亡。
the blood decreases. This can cause nutritional deficiency impaired enzymatic activity and increased mortality.
这种伤害带来的慢性肾病也会导致肾性骨病
Chronic kidney disease which can arise out of this injury precipitates uremic bone syndrome
侵蚀骨骼，使骨骼变脆易折。这可不是
a disorder that deforms the bones and weakens them causing them to fracture easily. This isn't something that you
你正长身体的年纪想发生的事。如果你的肾脏不工作了，你全身都会一直烂到
want to have while you're still growing as a human being. If your kidneys don't function your body down to its bones
骨子里，最终死在一滩本该尿出去的代谢废物中。这一切
will rot away and eventually you'll die in a pool of your own waste that should have been your urine. All of this seems
看上去有点不着边。横纹肌溶解症是一种古老的多因素疾病。
to be a non-intuitive series of events. Rhabdomyolysis is both a multifactorial and an ancient problem. Eating too much
吃太多利可瑞施（一种甘草提取的糖）会使人尿变深、肌肉疼。因为利可瑞施含有甘草酸
licorice candy can cause one to have dark urine and muscle aches. Licorice contains glycyrrhizic acid, a compound
它会提高皮质醇水平，导致低血钾，进而最终引发横纹肌溶解症
that keeps cortisol levels high in the body which leads to hypokalemia causing muscle breakdown and ultimately rhabdomyolysis
这在公元前300年古代中国就有记载，人们用甘草治疗
This was documented as far back as 300 BC by the ancient Chinese who used licorice as a remedy
消化不良。中国人叫这种病“横纹肌溶解症”。《旧约圣经·民数记》11章31-34记载：
for digestive disorders. They called it striped muscle dissolution. The Old Testament of the Bible numbers 11:31-34
犹太人出埃及时吃鹌鹑，闹了场大瘟疫。那个地区的鹌鹑在春季
Jews ate quail during their exodus from Egypt and suffered a great plague. Quail in that region eat hemlock herbs
横穿地中海迁徙时会吃毒堇草和种子，而毒堇含有毒芹碱，就是用来毒死
and seeds during their spring migration across the Mediterranean Sea. Hemlock contains coniine, the poison that was used
苏格拉底，导致他横纹肌溶解的毒药。拿破仑1806年在柏林期间，他的手下在指挥中心
to execute Socrates and that causes rhabdomyolysis. Napoleon occupied Berlin in 1806. His soldiers heated their living
烧煤取暖，他们因为通风不良吸入了不少一氧化碳，一氧化碳
quarters with burning coal. They breathed in carbon monoxide gas because of bad ventilation. Carbon monoxide binds
和血红蛋白强力结合，使肌肉缺氧，造成组织坏死
strongly to the hemoglobin in blood and starves your muscles of oxygen, causing the tissue to necrosis or die
从而导致横纹肌溶解症。在当时他们叫“坏疽”。二战期间，挤压综合征是由于
resulting in rhabdomyolysis. Back then they called it limb gangrene. In WWII, crush syndrome where the physical
轰炸后倒塌的建筑长时间压在肌肉组织上，导致
destruction through crushing of muscle tissue from falling objects due to bombings induced bruising underneath
肌肉严重损伤，同样是横纹肌溶解症。所以这问题没那么直接
severe muscle damage is known as rhabdomyolysis. So this isn't a direct problem as non-intuitive as it may be
直观看很难把泻药过量联系起来。有时让你拉臭臭的东西，还能让你肌肉溶解，进而损害
that overdosing on laxatives. Something that makes you poop causes your muscles to dissolve in your body thus damage
你的肾脏。那至于包哥的治疗也很简单，对症下药即可
your kidneys. Well at the very least the treatment for BG is very simple. We just go by the symptoms in this case
肌肉和肾脏能救回来，但他泻药吃多就只能忍着等它们全拉出去了
We can save his muscles and kidneys but he'll have to bear the pain of laxative overdose until it passes through his body
我们会给他注射钾元素，提高血钾水平，注射时时刻观察
We'll give him potassium supplement to raise his blood potassium levels we'll have to monitor it constantly
因为注射太多会让它心跳停止，太少又没用
because too much potassium will stop his heart and too little got him into the situation that he's in right now
血钾稳定后肌肉的溶解就停止了，就不会继续释放
keeping his potassium stable will prevent any more of his muscles from breaking down in his body and stop any further release
肌红蛋白。第二，它的肾脏因为脱水而血管收缩
of myoglobin. Second, because his kidneys have phase of constricted because they detected low blood volume then we
所以要给他静脉注水。不会让他喝因为吸收太慢
correct that by infusing water into his veins. We won't give it to him orally because the absorption will be too slow
这样身体含水量上来，肾脏血流量就提升
In this way it'll replace his body water and increase the amount of fluid going into his kidneys increasing renal
组织供氧也会恢复。就像洗一个筛子上的
perfusion allowing for more oxygen to get into that tissue. It's kind of like how we wash something out when things
脏东西一样。足够的补液就能最小化包哥之后的肾脏损伤。另外虽然
get trapped in a net. With enough fluid replacement will minimize any further renal damage to BG. Now while that renal
肾损伤是永久的，但至少还能用。在持续监护治疗
damage will stay forever in his medical history, at the very least his kidneys will still function. After monitoring and
对症下药之后，经历这一遭可算给他的后半生和他小伙伴上了一课
symptomatic treatment, a strong lesson learned and an experience that would never be lived down amongst his friends
包哥还算年轻，所以可以从他泻药过量导致的
for the rest of his life. BG, because he was so young, was able to recover from his laxative induced
低血钾进而横纹肌溶解症中恢复过来。泻药那玩意，千万吃多
hypokalemia and resulting rhabdomyolysis. Please don't ever take more than the recommended dose of laxatives for anything
这后果可不值当。感谢观看，祝大家身体健康！
It's just not worth the consequences. Thank you so much for watching take care of yourself and be well